Guide to the Charles Winslow Burpee Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Winslow Burpee collection
1872-1914
MS 1356
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Largely Yale memorabilia including programs, pins, and a model of the Yale fence. Also in the Charles Winslow Burpee collection are photographs of members of Skull and Bones ca. 1883 and related memorabilia.
Burpee, Charles W. (Charles Winslow), 1859-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Stiles Burpee, 1982; and Richard Guarelia, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This small collection contains items relating to Charles Winslow Burpee and to Yale College. Included are two undated letters to Burpee from friends and five communications concerning Skull and Bones. There is also a photograph of Skull and Bones members dating around 1883 and two impressions of the Skull and Bones seal. The remainder of the collection consists of Yale memorabilia such as programs, football tickets, Yale pins and other souvenir objects.
Arrangement
Arranged by record type.
Biographical / Historical
Charles W. Burpee: Yale, B.A., 1883; editor of Waterbury American (Ct.), 1883-1891; of Bridgeport Standard (Ct.), 1891-1895; of Hartford Courant, 1895-1904; with Phoenix Mutual Life Insurance Company 1904-1935; literary editor, Hartford Times, 1930-1935; author of books on Connecticut history.
Burpee, Charles W. (Charles Winslow), 1859-; Russell Trust Association, Inc; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1883; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Skull and Bones
    - Correspondence, 1882, 1904, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Photograph, [ca. 1883] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Seal (2), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yale memorabilia
    - Prom programs, 1882-1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yale News dinner program, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Football tickets, 1901-1902 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale fence model "1701-1901" (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale doll, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale football pin, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale ribbon pin, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Postcard of Elihu Yale's tomb, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified wooden object, "C. W. Burpee, July 29, 1872", 1872 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)